{
    "id": "cc26a804287b49c4bffcfa03a304223b",
    "title": "Intermediate Level Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I wish I ……………….. sing.",
            "description": "A past tense is used after wish to talk about unrealized hopes.",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "could",
                "will be able to"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She is tired ………………… hungry.",
            "description": "As well as means both...and...",
            "answers": [
                "as well as",
                "also",
                "as well"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The roses are very beautiful. Change into exclamatory.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "How beautiful are the roses!",
                "How beautiful the roses are!",
                "What beautiful the roses are!"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You cannot help him. He ……………….. (Change into passive)",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "cannot helped",
                "cannot be helped",
                "cannot be helping"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We saw a …………………. of ships in the harbor.",
            "description": "We say a fleet of ships. This is an example of a collective noun. ",
            "answers": [
                "pack",
                "fleet",
                "pride"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………. is thicker than water. (Complete the proverb.)",
            "description": "The correct expression is blood is thicker than water.",
            "answers": [
                "Blood",
                "Milk",
                "Ink"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We …………………….. at the party.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "enjoyed",
                "enjoyed ourselves",
                "enjoyed us"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The man said that he ……………………… to do a lot of work.",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the past tense, the verb in the subordinate clause too should be in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "had",
                "has had"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you write more clearly, everyone …………………. to read it.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "read",
                "reads",
                "will be able to"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "You …………………. stop arguing with me.",
            "description": "Had better is used to give strong advice. ",
            "answers": [
                "have better",
                "had better",
                "should better"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "There is hardly any water in the well, ……………………..?",
            "description": "Hardly is a negative word affirmative tags are used after negative statements. ",
            "answers": [
                "is there",
                "isn't there",
                "was there"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "At sixes and sevens means in a ………………………..",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "in a state of helplessness",
                "in a state of confusion",
                "in a state of shock"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}